Guide to the Yale University Military and Wartime Activities Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University military and wartime activities photographs
1898-1946
RU 750
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.25
(4 boxes, 3 folio folders)
The materials consist of photographs of Army and Navy Reserve Officers Training Corps (ROTC and NROTC), Signal Corps, Yale Batteries, and Civil Affairs Training program activities at Yale during World War I and World War II. Includes images of drilling instruction, exercises, and artillery practice. There are a few photographs of Yale students during the Spanish-American War.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 42-C (YRG 42-C), Records documenting military and wartime experiences of members of the Yale community.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs of Army and Navy Reserve Officers Training Corps (ROTC and NROTC), Signal Corps, Yale Batteries, and Civil Affairs Training program activities at Yale during World War I and World War II. Includes images of drilling instruction, exercises, and artillery practice. There are a few photographs of Yale students during the Spanish-American War.
General
Photograph depicting "military training exercise at the Payne Whitney Gymnasium, where students are learning to swim underwater while fully clothed" reported missing in 2014
Military training camps -- United States; World War, 1914-1918 -- Education and the war; World War, 1914-1918 -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Education and the war; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; Photographs; United States. Army. Reserve Officers' Training Corps; United States. Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps; Yale University. Reserve Officers' Training Corps
- Photographs Documenting Yale's Involvement with Military and Wartime Activities, 1898-1946
  General
  Photograph depicting "military training exercise at the Payne Whitney Gymnasium, where students are learning to swim underwater while fully clothed" reported missing in 2014
  - 1898 Spanish American War (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American University Union (World War I) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - World War I ROTC
    - Batteries A, B, C, and D (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Exercising, drilling, instruction, and practice (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Yale Batteries of field artillery at Tobyhanna, Pennsylvania (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - Instructors and officers; Equitation (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Informal and miscellaneous views; summer camp (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mobile hospital unit and Red Cross (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Service flags (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Alumni Day, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Hopkins Grammar School group (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Groups of unidentified individuals (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Commencement, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Faculty Battery recruits (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Armistice Day (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Aerial Coast Patrol Service (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - World War I Signal Corps (bound volume) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - World War I Navy ROTC
    - Exercising, drilling instruction, and practice (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Formal and parade views (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Informal views (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - World War I and World War II ROTC and Navy ROTC (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - ROTC 1927 Summer training camp (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - World War II ROTC
    - General (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Exercising, drilling instruction, and practice (Box 3, Folder 21 - 22)
    - Reviews, informal reviews (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - World War II Navy ROTC
    - Exercising, drilling instruction, and practice (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Review and marching scenes (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Informal views (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - World War II General
    - Ambulance donated by alumni (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ambulance given to England (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Army Air Corps (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Yale men in service (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Students picking fruit (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Committee on Student Preparation for War Service (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Students learning Malayan and Burmese (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous scenes (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Chinese print shop (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - OVERSIZE
    - World War I
      - ROTC and NROTC (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Officers and Men (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Chemical Warfare Service Unit, Medical School, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - World War II-Army Specialized Training Program
      - Chinese Section, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Company A, 1943-1944, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Company E, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Civil Affairs Training Program, 1943, 1945, 1946, 194? (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - General (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - FOLIO
    - Patriotic celebration in Hewitt Quadrangle, 1917 June (Box DR18F60)
    - Raising the flag in Hewitt Quadrangle, Circa 1917 (Box DR18F60)
    - Yale ROTC, Batteries A-I, 1917 (Box DR18F60)
    - Yale ROTC, Naval unit, 1917 (Box DR18F60)
    - Men in training, Yale athletic fields, 1916 (Box DR18F61)
    - Yale Batteries of Field Artillery, Tobyhanna, PA, 1916 (Box DR18F61)
    - Officers of the 10th Regiment, FANG of CT,Tobyhanna, PA, 1916 (Box DR18F61)
    - President Hadley presenting the colors to the Yale Field Artillery at Tobyhanna, PA, 1916 August (Box DR18F61)
    - Roster of Yale Batteries at Tobyhanna, PA, 1916 (Box DR18F61)
    - Yale ROTC Artillery at Fort Ethan Allen, VT, 1930 July (Box DR18F61)
    - Russian Language Group, Company A, 1944 (Box DR18F61)
    - World War I-military decorations (Box DR32F102)
    - Presentation of standards to 10th FANG of CT,Tobyhanna, PA, 1916 August (Box DR32F102)
    - Yale Batteries of Field Artillery, Tobyhanna, PA, 1916 August (Box DR32F102)
    - ROTC at athletic fields, Circa 1914 (Box DR32F102)
    - Company D-10th training regiment, Plattsburgh, NY, 1916 (Box DR32F102)
    - US Naval Unit, Yale University, 1918 December (Box DR32F102)
    - Naval Unit, Yale University, 1930 (Box DR32F102)
    - Signal Officers Training School, Yale University, 1918 (Box DR32F102)
    - Panoramic photograph of Company E Yale Students' Army Training Corps, 1918 November 7 (Box DR32F102)